# **Shelby Reyes**

Email: shelbyreyes90@gmail.com | Phone: 703-375-9031 | Media, Pennsylvania, 19063

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/shelbyreyes/ | GitHub: https://github.com/sdreyes | Website: http://shelbyreyes.net/

### **SUMMARY**

Full Stack Web Developer with experience using JavaScript, React, MySQL, Node.js, Express.js, CSS3, HTML5, and a variety of frameworks including Bootstrap and jQuery. Quick learner, patient teacher, and adept problem solver. Excellent interpersonal and written communication skills. Known among colleagues for keen eye for detail and superb organizational skills. Brings experience obtained through multi-faceted work environments including data-analysis, education, accounting, and customer service. Works effectively with a team using Agile Methodology.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, React, Express, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase, jQuery, Bootstrap, Handlebars.js, ORMs (Sequelize, Mongoose), Photoshop, WordPress, Git. 70 WPM typing speed. High level of PC literacy.

#### **PROJECTS**

Beadli | https://github.com/sdreyes/Beadli | http://bead.li/

A MERN-stack app that allows users to create, share, and browse pixel designs intended for fuse bead crafting.

- Co-developed with a team of four, my contributions to the project largely include the implementation of user authentication, bitmap image URI creation, and dynamic rendering of data.
- MongoDB, Express, React, Node, Mongoose, Passport.js, Bitmap.js, JavaScript, Bootstrap, CSS3, and HTML5

**Library Builder** | <a href="https://github.com/sdreyes/Library-Builder">https://google-books-sdreyes.herokuapp.com/</a> A MERN-stack app that allows users to search for and save books of interest through Google Books API.

MongoDB, Express, React, Node, Mongoose, Bootstrap, and Google Books API

**Progressive Scraper** | <a href="https://github.com/sdreyes/Progressive-Scraper">https://github.com/sdreyes/Progressive-Scraper</a> | <a href="https://progressive-scraper.herokuapp.com/">https://progressive-scraper.herokuapp.com/</a> | <a href="https://progressive-scraper.herokuapp.com/">https://progressive-scr

MongoDB, Mongoose, Cheerio, Node.js, Express, Handlebars.js, jQuery, and Bootstrap

# **EXPERIENCE**

**Teaching Assistant** – Trilogy Education Services, Penn LPS Coding Boot Camp – Philadelphia, PA **2019 - Present**Teach students full stack (MERN) web development skills, research and answer student questions, assist students with code activities and projects, and ensure smooth classroom activity transitions. *Key Accomplishments*:

Hosted several structured group tutoring sessions to help students with difficult JavaScript concepts

Office Manager – Federation Early Learning Services – Broomall, PA

2015 - 2019

Design and edit marketing materials for publishing, complete weekly payroll and schedules for a team of 16 employees, coordinate community events, troubleshoot problems with and repair office equipment, and run the front desk daily *Key Accomplishments*:

- Streamlined file and data tracking for 16 employees and 60 students by creating dynamic Excel spreadsheets
- Increased student enrollment by 20%

Administrative Assistant - Michaels Stores - Springfield, PA and Woodbridge, VA

2009-2015

Maintain store funds and payroll records, prepare daily deposits, investigate money discrepancies, and audit inventory *Key Accomplishments*:

- Increased the store's audit score by 7%
- Awarded "Michaels Loss Prevention Hero" certificate for outstanding customer service and detailed work

# **EDUCATION**

**University of Pennsylvania**, Philadelphia, PA – Full Stack Web Development Boot Camp Certificate **George Mason University**, Fairfax, VA – B.A. History